CLARANCE LIBERISTE NTWARI

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | VUE.JS & TYPESCRIPT & NODE.JS



ABOUT

RWANDA KIGALI

☐ LIBERINTWARI@GMAIL.COM

CLARANCELIBERI

✓ CLARANCELIBERI

IN/CLARANCE-LIBERISTE-NTWARI-27A484184 🗗

PROFICIENT LANGUAGES/FRAMEW ORK

PROFICIENT

TYPESCRIPT NODE.JS VUE.JS REACT.JS JAVA SPRING-BOOT GOLANG GIN

DATABASE

PROFICIENT

REDIS MONGODB MYSQL POSTGRESQL

OTHER LANGUAGES

WORKING

PYTHON GOLANG JAVA

DEVOPS

PROFICIENT

DOCKER ANSIBLE JENKINS GITLAB GCP AWS

METHODOLOGIES

SUMMARY

A software developer with over 6 years of experience developing modern web technologies solutions and has a passion for creativity, dedication, and ongoing personal growth. Has worked in small startups of 4 to large companies of 150 coworkers. Has led team of 10 in Agile methodologies and a track record of working remotely for 3 years, with a strong emphasis on team collaboration and efficient results

EXPERIENCE

RSSB, RWANDA (HYBRID)

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PIVOT ACCESS, RWANDA (ONSITE)

05/2023 - 01/2024

01/2024 - 01/2024

FULL STACK ENGINEER

I played a key role in the development of 'Tekana', a platform designed to manage the Rwanda National Police's daily operations, including traffic fines, driving license examinations, Moto Vehicle Inspection and license provisioning. Subsequently, as a seasoned Fullstack Engineer at Pivot Access here is what I did:

- Spearheaded the setup of micro frontends using React Next.js, enabling seamless collaboration across 7 independent modules without client disruptions
- Led and mentored a team of 12 frontend developers, emphasizing code reviews and adherence to best coding practices to maintain high code quality.
- Architected and implemented a CI/CD pipeline using GitLab, pnpm, Docker and Kubernates, slashing the time required for linting, testing, and deploying multiple micro frontends.
- Championed creating and deploying the Tekana Components library, crafted with React, TypeScript, and TailwindCSS. Ensured its availability on npm and chromatic for widespread use by various frontend teams.
- Developed comprehensive CI/CD pipeline flow charts and frontend project documentation, simplifying the onboarding process for new team members.
- Advocated and provided guidance on the implementation of Atomic Design principles, fortifying consistency and scalability within the component library.
- Pioneered the adoption of monorepo using PNPM and TurboRepo within the team, streamlining code and tool standardization across different teams.

BRITISH PETROLEUM (BP), UK (REMOTE)

07/2022 - 03/2023

SENIOR FRONTEND ENGINEER

Delivered significant contributions to different teams, improved user experiences, managed monorepo architecture, implemented CI/CD pipelines, and helped keep track of action logs on the Superfleet platform.

- Created an audit log module that records all user actions for traceability, In audit log team.
- Created micro-frontends with Webpack module federation and Vue.js, which improved the developer experience by 70%.
- Created different components under the Atomic Design principle and Storybook while making the BP design system, reducing component dependency by 35%.
- Wrote Regression and Unit tests of the components in the BP design System.

HUNTERSOFBOOK, TURKEY (REMOTE)

04/2021 - 06/2022

SOFTWARE FULL STACK ENGINEER

Improved frontend development and user engagement at HuntersOfBook through storybook UI components and WYSIWYG editor.

- Created Component presentation with storybook, which improved Developer experience by 15%.
- Wrote unit test and integration test respecting TDD with Jest and testinglibrary

PROFICIENT

AGILE SCRUM KANBAN ATOMIC DESIGN BEM

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH (PROFESSIONAL) KINYARWANDA (NATIVE)

- Built end-to-end APIs using Nest.js, PostgreSQL, Prisma, and Graphql.
- Developed a powerful WYSIWYG editor using Vue.js, an editor that made content writing smooth and faster with a 45% increase in efficiency for users.
- Wrote GitHub Action scripts for PRs, automating PR validations and automatic deployment, speeding up the normal manual process from 15mins to 55 secs.

MINISTRY OF ICT & RWANDA CODING ACADEMY, RWANDA(REMOTE)

SOFTWARE FULL STACK ENGINEER

08/2021 - 07/2022

Led a team and implemented features at Stunnity through analysis, design, mentorship, and efficient deployment using CI/CD pipeline.

- Led software analysis and design by making Software Requirement Specification (SRS), data dictionaries, DFD, and user use cases.
- Setup Gitlab Enterprise server, Jenkins, Tomcat, PM2, Docker, and Kubernetes for Java, Node.js, and Vue.js app CI/CD.
- Integrated 4 backend microservices and Frontend on Gitlab pipeline and deployment.
- Led a team of 10, Reviewed code and taught the team how to use modern software methodologies.
- Implemented different features on live streaming calls and chat with Node.js and Vue.is
- Wrote component and e2e tests using the react-testing library and Cypress.

KURIOUS LTD, RWANDA(REMOTE)

07/2018 - 03/2021

FRONTEND ENGINEER

Developed tools for video and textual materials for students and a real-time messaging service for communication between students and teachers, improving the platform's front-end, making the platform more competitive with Coursera and Edx.

- Developed and led software analysis and design process, resulting in the successful creation of over 20 Software Requirement Specification (SRS) documents, data dictionaries, DFD diagrams, and user use cases.
- Setup Gitlab Enterprise server, Jenkins, Tomcat, PM2, Docker, and Kubernetes for Java, Node.js, and Vue.js app CI/CD.
- Implemented DevOps workflows on Digital Ocean, speeding CI/CD process by 30%.
- Developed Chat, Live Stream, and Students Forum modules, resulting in a 50% increase in user engagement and communication, utilizing technologies such as webRTC, socket.io, Vue.js, and Kurento.

VOLUNTEER

FUTURE SKILLS BOOTCAMP

12/2019 - 12/2019

WEB DEVELOPMENT MENTOR

Taught programming concepts to 350 children under 18 during a two week program.

- Covered five skills including HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP, and SQL.
- Guided and facilitated students in presenting final projects on demo day.
- Facilitated students in designing web pages within 7 days, helping to foster competitive programming and creative thinking skills.

EDUCATION

RWANDA CODING ACADEMY

02/2019 - 07/2022

ASSOCIATE'S DEGREE SOFTWARE PROGRAMMING & EMBEDDED SYSTEM